(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-30T20:50:07.380412",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
みなさん、こんにちは！あずきです！
Hello everyone, I'm AZKi!
今日は一緒に盛り上がっていきましょう！
Let's get hyped up together today!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
ほう…どのくらい部屋の隅で薄まる日々に
Ah... for how long have I been fading in the corner of my room,
嫌気がさしてる
growing sick of it?
午前2時半少し手前
Just a little before 2:30 AM,
眠気にのまれて
swallowed by drowsiness,
全てを諦めてしまえば
if I just gave up on everything,
愚かなものだな すぐ忘れ去っていくから
how foolish, it'll all be forgotten so soon.
もう、日が暮れてしまう
The sun is already setting.
もう、明日が来てしまう
Tomorrow is already coming.
生きたくないと願った瞬間にさほら誰かが死ぬ
The moment I wished not to live, see, someone dies.
分かっていたのにどうして
Even though I knew, why?
どうして、どうして
Why, why?
世界はこんなにも 廻る、廻る、廻る、廻る
The world spins, spins, spins, spins so much
目が眩んで
that my eyes blur.
おかしくなりそうよ、もう一度だけ
I'm going crazy, just one more time...
世界はこんなにも 廻る、廻る、廻る、廻る
The world spins, spins, spins, spins so much
息もできないほどに私、疲れてしまったんだわ
that I can't even breathe, I've gotten so exhausted.
生きることに精一杯になりすぎてた 私、今、はっ…わっ…
Trying too hard just to live... right now, ah... wow...
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
散りばめた感情 四方にばらまいた感情
Scattered emotions, emotions spread in all directions,
逃げないここにない 嘘をついて姿を消して
there's no escape, not here, telling lies and erasing my form.
また、いくつも繰り返す また、後悔が重なる
Repeating it over and over again, regrets piling up once more.
ゼロからイチやり直して 生まれ変われば変われるはずとか
Starting over from zero to one, thinking I could change if I were reborn,
分かってないのにどうして どうして どうして
even though I don't get it, why, why, why?
ああー！
Aaaah!
夜から朝へ
From night to morning,
冬から夏へ
from winter to summer,
あなたは泣き寝入りした
you went to sleep crying.
少年少女たちがすれ違うこともなく
Boys and girls passing by without even crossing paths,
運命よ残酷だな、まあまあ…
destiny is so cruel, well, well...
世界はこんなにも ひとつふたつみっつよっついくつあるの？どれが正解なの？
The world is like this... one, two, three, four, how many are there? Which is correct?
世界はこんなにも 廻る、廻る、廻る、廻る、目が眩んで
The world spins, spins, spins, spins so much that my eyes blur,
おかしくなりそうよ、もう一度だけ
I'm going crazy, just one more time.
世界はこんなにも 廻る、廻る、廻る、廻る、声になれないほどに私叫んでしまったんだわ
The world spins, spins, spins, spins so much I can't even voice it, I ended up screaming.
生きるために傷つけて確かめた
Hurt others to live and confirmed it,
私、今、はっ…わっ…
me, right now, ha... wow...
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
ローテート・リピテッド
Rotate. Repeated.
法がない仕方
There's no other way.
どうかし てる 愛想 ない センス
Something's wrong, an expressionless sentence...
ねぇ 貸して きれいな 細胞を
Hey, lend me some clean cells!
たった一度の皆勤賞
The only time with perfect attendance!
帰り道にどうか気をつけて
Please take care on your way back home,
きっとあなたの人生が 素敵なものでありますように
hoping that your life will be wonderful.
告白の途中
In the middle of a confession,
飽きもせずに生きてクレイジー
living crazy without getting tired.
その歴史に混ぜてよ
Mix me into that history!
目が回るような人生相談
A dizzying life consultation,
その呪文は無詠唱
that spell is chantless.
誰にも言えないことをしよう
Let's do something no one else can talk about,
気が狂ったフリして恋をしよう
let's fall in love pretending to go crazy.
また は 破裂そうなくれざる心のとキめき
Once again, the heart-pounding excitement...
1000年先でも
Even 1,000 years from now,
きっとずっと踊りましょう
let's keep dancing forever.
再着火不能な愛
Unalterable love...
どうかし て る 愛想 ない センス
Something's wrong, an expressionless sentence...
ねぇ 貸して きれいな 細胞を
Hey, lend me some clean cells!
たった一度の皆勤賞
The only time with perfect attendance!
帰り道にどうか気をつけて
Please take care on your way back home,
きっとあなたの人生が 素敵なものでありますように
hoping that your life will be wonderful.
告白の途中
In the middle of a confession,
飽きもせずに生きてクレイジー
living crazy without getting tired.
その歴史に混ぜてよ
Mix me into that history!
目が回るような人生相談
A dizzying life consultation,
その呪文は無詠唱
that spell is chantless.
誰にも言えないことをしよう
Let's do something no one else can talk about,
気が狂ったフリして恋をしよう
let's fall in love pretending to go crazy.
また は 破裂そうなくれざる心のとキめき
Once again, the heart-pounding excitement...
1000年先でも
Even 1,000 years from now,
きっとずっと踊りましょう
let's keep dancing forever.
再着火不能な愛
Unalterable love...
この世で造花より綺麗な花はないわ
There is no flower in this world more beautiful than an artificial one,
何故ならば全ては嘘で出来ている
because everything is made of lies.
antipathy world
絶望の雨はあたしの傘を突いて
The rain of despair pierces my umbrella,
湿らす前髪とこころの裏面
dampening my bangs and the reverse side of my heart.
煩わしいわ
How annoying!
何時しか言の葉は疾病に枯れきって
Before I knew it, words had long since withered away,
事の真実があたしに熟れている
and the reality of the matter has ripened in me.
鏡に映り嘘を描いて
Reflected in the mirror, painting lies,
自らを見失った絵画
a painting that lost sight of itself.
パパッパラパッパララッパッパ
Pa-pa-pa-ra, pa-pa-ra, ra-pa-ppa,
謎々 かぞえて遊びましょう
let's count riddles and play!
タタッタリアッタララッタッタ
Ta-ta-tta, ra-tta-ra, ra-tta-tta,
何故何故 此処で踊っているのでしょう
why, why are we dancing here?
簡単なことも解らないわ
I don't even understand simple things,
あたしって何だっけ
what was my name again?
それすら夜の手に見絆されて
Even that was dragged into the hands of the night,
愛のように 消える 消える
like love, disappearing, disappearing.
さようならも言えぬ嚠喨いた
I cried without even being able to say goodbye.
フォニー フォニー フォニー
Phony, phony, phony,
嘘に絡まれているあたしは
I am entangled in lies!
antipathy world
何時しか空の音が嫌に鳴り合って
Before I knew it, the sound of the sky was clashing hatefully,
色の目があなたを融かしている
and the colors of the eyes are melting you.
鏡に映るあたしを欠いて
Slighting the me reflected in the mirror,
誰しもが見間違えた虚像
an illusion that everyone mistook.
Fake Fake Fake
如何して愛なんてものに群がり
Why do people flock to things like love
それを欲して生きるの囚
and live desiring it?
今日も泳いでいる夜の電車が通っていく
The night train, swimming as usual, passes by.
踊り明かせよ
Dance until dawn!
何故何故 此処が痛むのでしょう
Why, why does it hurt here?
散々な日々は変わらないわ
The miserable days never change.
絶望の雨は止まないわ
The rain of despair won't stop,
さようならも言えぬ嚠喨いた
I cried without even being able to say goodbye.
嘘に絡まれているあたしは ただ
Entangled in lies, just...
簡単なことも解らないわ
I don't even understand simple things,
あたしって何だっけ
what was my name again?
それすら夜の手に見絆されて
Even that was dragged into the hands of the night,
愛のように 消える 消える
like love, disappearing, disappearing.
さようならまたねと呟いた
I muttered goodbye and see you again...
嘘に絡まれているあたしは
I, entangled in lies.
こんな異常だけの世界で
In this world of anomalies only,
存在意義探してんだ
I'm searching for my reason to exist.
何を言われても満たされることないよ
No matter what I'm told, I'm never fulfilled,
感覚すら fake
even my senses are fake.
偽物ばかり全部 うわべで飾って誤魔化して
All just fakes, decorating the surface to deceive,
何が善か悪か分からないから壊れていく
I don't know what's good or evil, so I'm breaking down.
一体何が正気か知れないから
Just what is sanity? I don't know,
従ってしまって
so I just end up obeying.
一体何に本気なんだっけ 自問自答を繰り返して
What was I even serious about? Repeating self-questioning,
ああ、夜空の真下さまよっている
Ah, wandering right beneath the night sky.
こんな魔ガモノの世界は
In this world of monsters,
自分を見失いそうだ
I feel like I'm losing myself.
痛みなど感じないで生きていたい
I want to live without feeling any pain.
生きていたい
I want to live.
こんな魔ガモノの世界は
In this world of monsters,
自分を見失いそうだ
I feel like I'm losing myself.
「助けて」叫んだら救いの手はありますか？
If I scream "help", is there a saving hand?
願望すら fake
Even my desires are fake.
もう疲れてしまったよ
I'm already so tired.
何度でもやり直せたらいいのに
If only I could start over as many times as I want...
こんな異常だけの世界で
In this world of anomalies only,
存在意義探してんだ
I'm searching for my reason to exist.
形のない自由なリアどこですか？
Where is freedom without shape?
こんな異常だけの世界で
In this world of anomalies only,
存在意義探してんだ
I'm searching for my reason to exist.
何を言われても満たされることないよ
No matter what I'm told, I'm never fulfilled,
感覚すら fake
even my senses are fake.
全ては fake
Everything is fake.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
皆さん改めてまして、AZKiです！
Everyone, once again, I'm AZKi!
いや皆さん、夜遅い時間ですね
Man, everyone, it's late at night, isn't it?
夜遅い時間ですけれども、皆さん盛り上がってますか？起きてますか？元気ですか？
Even though it's late, are you all hyped? Are you awake? Doing well?
はい、えーっとですね、今日はYouTube Music Weekend Special LIVEとしまして、AZKiのライブをここで披露しております！
Yes, um, today for YouTube Music Weekend Special LIVE, I'm performing right here!
イェーイ！
Yay!
はい、えーっとですね、今日はあの普段応援してくれてる開拓者様、の、開拓者の皆はもちろんですね、それ以外のひともきっと、きっと何かの縁できっと見てくれてるかなと思うので
Right, of course to all the Kaitakusha who always support me, and everyone else watching by some connection,
AZKiのライブはこれだぞというところをですね、えー見ていただきたいなと思っておりますので、一緒にコメントとか、えっと、盛り上げてくれると嬉しいです！よろしくねー！イェーイ！
I want you to see what an AZKi live show is really like, so I'd be happy if you cheer along in the comments! Yay!
ということで、3曲お聴きいただきました。水を飲んでいいですか？水を、ええ、水飲みますよ。よっこいしょ。
So, you've heard three songs. Can I drink some water? Water, yeah, I'll drink some. Heave-ho.
お水を補給したところで
Having replenished my water,
次はですね、あの曲を、あの曲を歌いたいと思います！
next, I'd like to sing that song, that song!
それでは聴いてください。「Shiny Smily Story」
With that, please listen to it. "Shiny Smily Story"
We took our hands towards the brightest screens
All we wish are shining dreams
We make our choice with different voice
Oh, yes we know get set and go!
You were the one who set this light of smile
It was a dark and hopeless place
It was your shiny eyes that caught me
Filled with hope, this story starts now
Notice the fear inside me bouncing up?
That’s when i tune my heart beat down
I will shine, i will smile, my wish will come true
The first page of my history
Voice telling me to “give it up”
Voice telling me to "give it up"
Touch the sky and shine, just reach out
You're my happy star
I wish I, I wish my, my dearest wishes come true
The past page, my history
Go steady, meet the day, give it up, there is always a wall in my hands up
I will never be alone, no, no anymore
We are the shiny, smiley star!
Reach to the hands, oh, what applauded the dreams, giving you all the another team
I'll play your mind, now take my hand, the shortest one of dreaming on
Access through my heart, you will see, no regrets recalled degree
We make a choice with different words
Oh, yes we know, cuz set and go
Oh, yes we know, 'cause set and go
Reach to the top of my sky ever, my precious shiny smiley days
It's a light you have never seen before
Sending for you, come on and get it
Do you remember what a love did you get? Is always here with me I'll stay
Everyone's, everyone's, I get from you, but not enough, I want it more
My precious mind is like a spell, I'm magic, those that make you smile
You'll never see my tears, if it disappears
'Cause it's my shiny, smiley light!
Reach to the hands, oh, what applauded the dreams, one day, story never to scream
Together we can make it free, a never ending story
Everyone's, shining to stay, feeling love, the shinyest smile
We make a choice with different words, oh, yes we know
Cuz set and go
'Cause set and go
Where I'm stuck, you give your way, you are so I feel that
Touch my skin and you will feel my cuts here, whenever you need, there will be no tear
The speed we stride ever, each tears look out my future shining Lord
Make everyone's to know, my shiny smile
Reach to the hands, oh, what applauded the stage, this is me in my shiny base
Tear of joy and grow, happy days, just a starts that we have just made
Hold my hands to see our midnight, breeze my dream come true for my life
Listen these stars, step by step, a miracle!
Reach to the hands, oh, what applauded the dreams, giving you all the another team
I'll play your mind, now take my hand, the shortest one of dreaming come true
Access through my heart, you will see, no regrets my heart is so free
We make a choice with different words
Oh, yes we know, cuz set and go
Oh, yes we know, 'cause set and go
Create our world
壊してなくなった壁は いつかあったことも忘れて
The walls we broke down and lost, forgetting they were ever there
壊すためのその拳は 何を作るの？
What are those fists meant for breaking going to create?
離れた星の住人が わけも知らずまたぶつかり合っている
Inhabitants of distant stars collide once again without knowing why
ステージのバックライトは 背中に感じるだけじゃない
The stage backlight is not just felt on your back
次に立つ誰かのために 輝いている
It shines for whoever stands next
今すぐ世界は変わらないけど
The world won't change right away, but
11年後の君に歌うよ
I'll sing to you 11 years from now
今日も夜空はこんなに冷たいのに
Even though tonight's night sky is so cold
この街の灯はいつも熱い
The lights of this town are always warm
一人ひとりのストーリーが あふれているから
Because everyone's individual stories are overflowing
飛び出せ世界へ、届け未来へ、shiny parade!
Jump out to the world, reach to the future, shiny parade!
Wow Wow 飛び立てば正解！
Wow Wow, taking flight is the right answer!
自信持って もっと激しく遊べ
Have confidence and play even harder!
My sister
今もセイザデイ
Even now, seize the day!
全部叶えていこう
Let's make all of them come true!
夢見る力が 地上を照らせば
If the power to dream illuminates the earth,
誰かの好きと 繋がってソラテイク
It connects with someone's love and takes to the sky!
またいつか花開くよ ソラサイク
Someday flowers will bloom again, sky cycle!
ぼくら自分と世界の時間を混同しがちで
We often confuse our time with the world's time,
世界が大人になってると勘違いして
And mistakenly think the world has grown up.
あるときループから放り出されて
Then suddenly being thrown out of the loop,
変わり映えしない日々に戸惑う
We get bewildered by unchanging days.
誰かの夢が 連鎖してゆくのは
Why someone's dream chains on
自由を縛る 鎖じゃなくて
Isn't a chain that binds freedom,
少しずつでも まだ見ぬ世界
But even little by little, if we can see
見えたらいいよね
A world we haven't seen yet, that'd be nice, right?
飛び出せセイハドー
Leap out, conquer the wave!
響け究極的ビックウェイブ
Resonate, the ultimate big wave!
瞳輝かせた君が好きさ
I love you with your sparkling eyes!
My sister
今もセイザデイ
Even now, seize the day!
いつも全身全霊
Always with all my heart and soul!
磁力線の向こう側 目指して 一瞬の成功が
Aiming beyond the magnetic field lines, a fleeting success
永遠になってSpark
Becomes eternity, Spark!
この世界を変えてくよ ソラサイク
I'll change this world, sky cycle!
懐かしいこと 心地いいとき
When nostalgic things feel comfortable,
新しいことは 辛いこと
New things feel painful.
それでも 新しい 明日がみたい
Even so, I want to see a new tomorrow!
飛び出せセイハドー
Leap out, conquer the wave!
届け未来的新ショウタイム
Reach it, the futuristic showtime!
自信持って もっと激しく遊べ
Have confidence and play even harder!
My sister
今もセイザデイ
Even now, seize the day!
全部叶えていこう
Let's make all of them come true!
夢見る力が 地上を照らせば
If the power to dream illuminates the earth,
誰かの好きと 繋がってソラテイク
It connects with someone's love and takes to the sky!
またいつか花開くよ ソラサイク
Someday flowers will bloom again, sky cycle!
ぼくらの今が 君を動かして
Our present moves you,
またいつか花開くよ ソラサイク
Someday flowers will bloom again, sky cycle!
少しずつ近づいているよ 夢見たトキメキ
Getting a little closer, the excitement I dreamed of,
広がっていく世界中に 皆を笑顔にするキラメキを
Spreading across the expanding world, making everyone smile with this sparkle!
一人じゃないから ライバルがいるから
Because I'm not alone, because there are rivals,
競い合うこと すら楽しくなっちゃうんだよ
Competing against each other becomes so much fun!
dear my friends
未来へ走り出したら fantastic
When we start running toward the future, it's fantastic!
夢を咲かせて our future
Let's make our dreams bloom, our future!
一歩一歩を踏み出して トップを目指そう
Step by step, let's step out and aim for the top!
信じる力が 心の happiness 全力で楽しもう
The power to believe is the heart's happiness, let's enjoy it with all our might!
それは いつかきっと 大きな 夢 叶えるから
That will surely someday make a big dream come true!
dreaming days
ずっと…ドリミネイス
Always... dream in days,
答えのない道を行く
Walking down a path with no answers,
誰も見たことのない 大世界 連れていくよ
I'll take you to a grand world that no one has ever seen.
みんなのこと確保はいいかな
Are you all ready to secure your spots?
手を離さないで ひとりじゃ遠いから
Don't let go of my hand, because alone it's too far.
信号が見ているから 初めての挑戦すが
The signals are watching, so this first challenge...
楽しくなっちゃうんだよ ひとりぼっち
Gets so fun, even when you're all alone.
奇跡を巻き起こすんだ グローリーデイズ
Stirring up miracles, glory days,
夢に近づいてマイストーリー 小さな蕾が咲き誇るまで
getting closer to my story until the small bud blooms proudly.
挑戦し続けるんだ ブリリアンシア
I'll keep challenging myself, brilliancia.
全力で飛び込もう 本能 少しだけの勇気がいま遅れたんだ
Let's dive in with full power on instinct; a little courage came just a bit too late.
ずっと…ドリミネイス
Always... dream in days,
選んできた未来の選択肢 すべてがほらあたしたちを作った
Every choice of the future I've picked formed who we are;
選ぶことの中身がさえた意味があったと気づいたよ
I realized there was a clear meaning behind choosing.
涙を流した数が愛おしい
The number of tears I shed is so dear,
この心がおばけのように大きくなりたい
I want this heart to grow as big as a ghost.
未来へ走り出したら ばっちり全力で楽しもう
Once we run towards the future, let's enjoy it fully!
それはいつかきっと大きくて遠くなったり トップになりたい
That will someday surely become big and distant, wanting to reach the top.
未来へ走り出したら ばっちり 全力で楽しもう
Once we run towards the future, let's enjoy it with all our might.
それはいつかきっと 大きな夢へ叶えるから ドリミネイス
That will someday surely fulfill a big dream, dream in days,
走り続けていくんだ グレイトフル ひとりじゃ届かない高みへ
Running onward, grateful, to heights we can't reach alone.
ありがとう
Thank you!
はい、ということで AZKiお水タイム。
Yes, so... AZKi water time.
はい。
Yep.
みんなもお水を補給してもらって。
Everyone go ahead and hydrate too.
はい、ということで、ちょっとまたMCなんですけれども、
So anyway, it's a bit more MC time,
ちょっとね、なんか、こう改めて、なんかちょっとみんなにこういうこうい場で、ちょっとお話し、なんかしようと思って。
but I wanted to talk to everyone like this in a setting like this.
ちょっとね、最近ちょっと考えていることをね、ここで、まあ深夜のね、深夜のテンションでちょっとお話ししたいと思っているんです。
I've been thinking about something lately, and I wanted to talk about it here, in a late-night mood.
ええと、先日、ええと、私の大好きなカースちゃん棟のですね、あの深海2のビルディングか、が終わってから、
Um, the other day, um, after my beloved Kasho-chan's Deep Sea 2 rebuilding finished, um,
AZKiのライブとかその、普段ね一緒に活動しているAZKiチームの、なんかこう良さってなんだろうな、ということをですね、とてもとても考えてまして、
I thought very much about what makes AZKi's live shows and the AZKi team we usually work with so great,
そう、めちゃくちゃあのね、話したりしてたんですけど、はい、なんか
and yeah, we talked about it a lot, but yeah...
なんかこう、歌唱ちゃんのこうライブとかってすごくすごく、なんかこう物語とか、なんかこう圧倒的な、なんか世界観とか、なんかそういうのがあって、
Kasho-chan's live shows have such incredible stories, overwhelming worldviews, and things like that,
それがすごくAZKiは好きで、いつも心を推し静かさにされ、しばらく放心状態みたいなことがよくあるんですけど。
that AZKi loves so much, and it always quiets my heart, leaving me in a daze for a while.
なんかこう なんかそれの なんか劣化版というか
You know, sometimes it feels like a degraded version...
模倣でしか なんかちょっとなかったりとか
or just an imitation,
なんかね 実際そうやって思うところが、まああるわけですよ。
and well, there are times when I actually think that way.
まあ色々とね、活動している中で いろんなものを目にして、体験して、自分たちはどうだろうって結構振り返ることがあるんですけど、
Through various activities, seeing and experiencing many things, I often look back and wonder how we're doing.
でも、なんかそんな中で、まあこうやって開拓者のみんなが、AZKiのことをなんでこう、なんで……
But even so, among all that, seeing all you pioneers support AZKi like this—well, saying "why"...
なんていうとちょっと変かもしれないんですけど、
saying "why" might sound a bit strange,
なんか、なんで応援してくれているんだろう、と
but I often wonder why you all cheer me on.
ええ、考え、まあしてですね、考えて、ま、で、そこ、それってきっと、あの、歌が好きだったりとか、
Thinking about it... well, surely it's because you love the singing,
こうやってなんか普段話してる感じが好きだったりとか、いろいろあると思うんですけど、
or because you like the way I talk normally, or various other reasons.
なんかこう、昔からね、ま、ずっと一緒に歩いてくれているみんなは、こうなんだろうな、
But everyone who has walked with me for a long time... compared to the very beginning,
まあ最初から比べるとめちゃくちゃに変化したと思うんですよ。
I think you've changed dramatically.
AZKiの歴史を辿るといろんなことがあって、ま、そうやって、そういうなんだろうな、変化っていうのを一緒にこうやって楽しんで
Tracing AZKi's history, a lot has happened, and I feel like we've been enjoying those changes together.
くれているのかなというふうに思って、思っていまして（笑）考えて……
Thinking that you've been enjoying those changes with me... I always think that.
だからやっぱり常にね、なんかこう、目標とか、なんかこう新しい姿とか、
That's why I always need to keep aiming for new goals, new appearances,
なんか挑戦とか、なんか変化し続けられないといけないし、ま、だからね、こうやって新しいね、衣装になってからもね、こうね、
and new challenges, continuing to change. So even after getting this new outfit,
あの応援し始めてくれた開拓者のみんなもいると思うんですけど、ええ、そうゆ、なんかそのいろんな場面でこうやってAZKiに出会ってくれた開拓者のみんなと、
I'm sure there are pioneers who started supporting me recently. To all of you who met AZKi in various situations,
これからも、えっと一緒に変化っていうのを、なんか楽しんでいきたいなと思って、思っていまして、
I want us to enjoy these changes together from now on. I truly feel that way.
だからこそ、こうやって開拓者のみんなの、なんか1つ1つのコメントとか、えっと、そういうのを大事にして、
That's why I cherish every single comment and support from all the pioneers,
これからも頑張っていきたいと、思っていま、す。まあこの世界はね、うん、ノウフィクション、今日のライブタイトルにもありますが、
and I want to keep doing my best. As today's live title "NON-FICTION" says,
ノンフィクションです。えーと、厳しいこともたくさんあるんですけど、今AZKiが歌っていて、
this world is non-fiction. There are many harsh things, but right now, as I sing,
開拓者のみんなが応援してくれて、場所や時間をこうやって飛び越えて、いろんな気持ちを共有できるっていうのは、本当にかけがえのないことだと思います。
and all of you pioneers support me, transcending time and space to share our feelings—that is truly irreplaceable.
息をしている だから生きている
I'm breathing, therefore I'm alive.
何度もずっと 言葉を尽くしてきたんだ
Countless times, I've poured out my words.
息をしている ように見えている
It looks as though I'm breathing.
青が滲み出す 私にとっての何か
A blue seeping out, something essential to me.
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heartbeat thuds wildly away.
孤独が毒々している
Seriously, what a ridiculous story.
叩かれても腐らずに
Roll it up, smoke it, inhale, and spit it out again.
ここで歌うよ ボタンひとつ
Let's sing right here, with just a single button.
気持ち
With these feelings...
最後まで私をこと覚えててくれるの
Can you keep remembering me until the very end?
消えてしまいそうなの 分かってよ 分かってよ ねぇ
It feels like it's about to vanish—don't you understand?
とことん孤独なの 恋人惜しみ違うのさ
Even such loneliness, love, and a white lie are mismatched.
君が忘れちゃったら 私は痛くなるの
If you forget me, I'll start to hurt.
命のような夢を見てるよ またね バイバイ
Seeing dreams like life itself, goodbye again.
息をしてる 宝物生きている
Breathing hard, living preciously.
血の証明を 欲しがって 欲しがっているんだ 音が止まって 褪なくなって
Wanting to prove it, wanting it so badly that the world stops and fades away...
そんな私を 君は笑ってくれるかな
Can you laugh at someone like me?
孤独が毒々している
Seriously, what a ridiculous story.
叩かれても腐らずに
Even if I'm beaten, I won't rot away.
ここで歌うよ 気分次第で
Let's sing right here, with just how I feel.
最後まで私のこと見届けてくれるの
Can you keep remembering me until the very end?
覚めてしまいそうなの 分かってよ 分かってよ ねぇ
It feels like I'm waking up—don't you understand?
声だけ届くんだよ 塩辛い涙が出てじゃおうぞ
Even voice can reach you, let's let out salty tears.
君が忘れちゃったら 私は痛くなるの
If you forget me, I'll start to hurt.
命のような夢を見てるよ またね バイバイ
Seeing dreams like life itself, goodbye again.
吐き込んだあの日を 軽くいじらないで やめて それが生きてるってことだから
Swallowing down that day we swallowed, don't mess with it lightly—stop it, that's how you live.
大丈夫 ずっと私は歌い続けるから
It's okay, I'll keep singing forever.
最後まで私は生きているか分からないけど 君がくれた言葉は確かに残ってる
Until the very end, I wonder if I'm alive. The words you gave me certainly remain.
最後まで私のこと覚えててくれるの いつ死んでしまうんだろ 分かんない 分かんないよ ねぇ
Until the very end, can I keep remembering your words? I don't know when I'll die.
痛いくらい気持ちがシンクロする時もあるけど 君が忘れちゃったら
Even when my heart hurts and feels out of sync, if you forget me...
私は痛くなるの 命のような夢を見てるよ またね バイバイ
I'll start to hurt, seeing dreams like life itself, goodbye again.
うつむいた顔はひどく弱いことに気づいたの
I realized my cast-down face was terribly weak.
この先には 叶えたいことや 夢があるから
Because ahead of this, there are things I want to fulfill and dreams.
目をそらさないように 正解はない
So I won't avert my eyes, there is no single right answer.
誰だって一人で 思うまま始まってく この物語
Everyone begins alone, unfolding just as they wish, this story.
今はただ走って 季節を駆け巡って 見えないくらい闇の中で
Now just running, dashing through the seasons, in a darkness so deep it's invisible,
痛みだってあるよ 戸惑いだってたあるよ
there is pain, there is bewilderment too.
それでもここで生きていくと 決めたんだ
Even so, I decided to live on right here.
決めたから 前を向いて
Because I decided, looking forward...
生き方を誰かに決められて
Having my way of life decided by someone else
本当はそうじゃなかったって 今さら嘆いたって
and lamenting now that it wasn't really what I wanted—
味方もヒーローも現れなくて 喧騒の中でふとがむしゃらに駆けていたんだ
neither allies nor heroes appeared, running recklessly amidst the hustle and bustle.
この先には 奏でたいことや 疑いがあるから
Because ahead of this, there are things I want to play and doubts.
耳を塞ぎすますように 間違いはない
So as to strain my ears, there are no mistakes.
誰だって一人で 綴り綴られていく この物語
Everyone alone, being spelled out letter by letter, this story.
過去今未来が あなたを駆け巡って いそうよ現実の中で
Past, present, and future rush through you, right within reality.
泣きたくもなるよ 諦めたくなるよ
I feel like crying, I feel like giving up.
それでもここで生きていくと 決めたんだ
Even so, I decided to live on right here.
決めたから 走り出そうよ
Because I decided, let's start running.
生まれ変わっても この話をしよう この人生でよかったと
Even if I'm reborn, let's talk about this story: that I'm glad I had this life.
痛みは力に 戸惑いは期待に
Pain turns into strength, bewilderment turns into expectation.
そうしてここで生きていくと
And so, deciding to live on right here,
今はただ走って 季節を駆け巡って 見えないくらい闇の中で
now just running, dashing through the seasons, within a darkness so deep it's invisible,
痛みだってあるよ 戸惑いだってたあるよ
there is pain, there is bewilderment too.
それでもここで生きていくと 決めたんだ
Even so, I decided to live on right here.
決めたから 前を向いて
Because I decided, looking forward...
ありがとう。
Thank you.
はい、ということでお届けしたのは命と、小さな心が決めたこと、でした！
Yes, so what I delivered to you was 'Inochi to Chiisana Kokoro ga Kimeta Koto'!
なんと、ね、このセカンドの衣装にチェンジしまして歌わせていただきました。
And so, I changed into this second outfit and sang it for you.
はい、ということで早いものでラスト、3曲、ということで、
Yes, time flies, and we are down to the last three songs.
ここからはノンストップでいきたいと思っているので、
From here on, I want to keep going non-stop,
MCはこれで最後になります。
so this will be my final MC.
その前に、お水飲もう。お水、お水。
Before that, let's have some water. Water, water.
軸を越えて、えいしょ、軸を越えてお水飲んできました。
I crossed over the axis—oops—crossed over the axis to drink some water.
はい、ということで、ね、サード、サード衣装にチェンジしまして、ラスト3曲をお届けしたいと、思います。
Yes, so I changed into my third outfit, and I'd like to deliver the final three songs.
え、さっきですね、ちょっと
Um, earlier, I sort of...
話下りなんですけど、えーと、
So, to change the subject, um...
今日はこのスペシャルライブ、ノンフィクションということで、
today, for this special live concert, "NON-FICTION,"
ノンフィクションなこの世界で えー、変化し続けることを大切していきたいし、
in this non-fiction world, um, I want to cherish continuing to change,
こういうね、非日常のこういうライブは もちろん、まあ、普段やっているAZKiんちの日常の配信でも どんどん変化していけるようになっていきたいと思います。
and of course, in extraordinary live performances like this, as well as in my everyday AZKi-inchi streams, I want to keep evolving and changing.
え、開拓者の皆と一緒に歩いてきた歌を残していきたいと思っています。
Um, I want to leave behind the songs we've walked together with all the pioneers.
だから、これからも一緒に歩いて行こうね。
So let's keep walking together from now on too.
それでは、聞いてください。「インディスワールド」
Now then, please listen to "In this world."
愛が言葉を見失っている
Love is losing its words,
空が涙を降らせていたんだ
the sky was shedding tears.
誰のために 何のために
For whose sake? For what purpose?
これが運命だと言うの？
Are you saying this is destiny?
嘘が街を包み込んでいる
Lies are wrapping around the town,
鳥が飛べず声を上げていた
birds couldn't fly and raised their voices.
たった一つの存在を灯す
Lighting up a single existence,
この場所で君を待っている
I'm waiting for you in this place.
世界はとても苦しそうでした
The world looked so painful;
私に何ができるというの？
what could I possibly do?
歌うことが正しいかなんて
Whether singing is right or not,
今も答えは見つからないけど
I still haven't found the answer, but
確かなのは君がいたから
what's certain is that you were here,
私はここにいるの
so I am here.
何回何十回だって君と出会うから
No matter how many tens of times, I will meet you again and again,
夜が明けていく 光が降り注ぎ
as the night breaks and light pours down,
喜び 悲しみ を抱え 前を向く
embracing joy and sorrow, looking forward.
君と生きる ここで この場所で
Living with you, here, in this place—
それが私の世界だ
that is my world.
その一秒一瞬が煌めく yeah
Every single second sparkles, yeah.
過去が虹を壊したとしても
Even if the past destroyed the rainbow,
夢が街を食らい尽くそうとしても
even if dreams try to devour the town,
大丈夫だからそばにいるよ
it's alright, so I'll be by your side.
君に笑ってほしいんだ
I want you to smile.
生まれた意味を探しているの
Searching for the meaning of why we were born,
転んでもただ走り続けていく
falling down yet just continuing to run,
現実を知って明後日を嘆いた
knowing reality and lamenting the future,
心が叫びたがってる
my heart is crying out.
タイムマシンに乗ってさ
Riding in a time machine,
別の未来を選ぶことができたなら
if I could choose a different future,
君のいない世界を創造する？
would I create a world without you?
そんな世界は想像できない
I can't even imagine such a world.
君に届きますように
May this reach you—
この声が この歌が
this voice, this song.
何回何十回だって君を選ぶから
No matter how many tens of times, I choose you,
夜が滲んでいく 地平線の彼方へ
as the night bleeds away beyond the horizon,
響く呼吸の音を確かに感じた
I firmly felt the sound of echoing breath.
始めよう君との未来を
Let's begin our future together,
繋いだ手を離さないで
don't let go of our joined hands.
大きな声で名前を呼んで
Call my name out in a loud voice,
奇跡を駆け抜けて
running through miracles—
どこまでも行けるよ
we can go anywhere.
ここからもう一度君と私で始めよう
Let's start over once more, you and I, right here.
無限の中に生まれた物語を
A story born in infinity,
君と歩いていく
walking together with you.
この世界が悲しみに溢れたとしても
Even if this world overflows with sorrow,
私は歌を歌い続けていく
I will keep on singing songs.
君と生きる ここで この場所で
Living with you, here, in this place—
それが私の世界だ
that is my world.
その一秒一瞬が煌めく yeah
Every single second sparkles, yeah.
傷つき涙を流す君が
May you, who get hurt and shed tears,
幸せだと思える世界になりますように
find a world where you can feel happy.
願いを込め歌う
Singing with all my heart.
この扉の向こうが未開の可能性なら
If the other side of this door is unexplored potential,
現実を動かすのか？
can we set reality in motion?
暗闇を手探りで 不安と焦燥の中で
Groping in the dark, amidst anxiety and impatience,
こぼれる光を見た
I saw the spilling light.
手を伸ばして この未来はキミのものだから
Reaching out, because this future belongs to you,
時間を超えて 繋ぐよ
I'll connect it across time.
ココロが今 創造するの 私のストーリー
My heart now creates my own story.
声を聞かせて キミを知りたいから
Let me hear your voice, because I want to know you.
輝かせよう 新しい世界
Let's make a new world shine.
生まれた意味を 見つけるのさ
I'm going to find the meaning of my birth.
全てが始まる この場所で
In this place where everything begins,
声が枯れるまで 叫んで
shout until your voice goes hoarse.
言葉に傷つけられ 悲しみがこぼれるのは
Being hurt by words, if sadness spills over,
弱いからじゃないよ 勇気はあるから
it's not because you're weak, you have the courage.
踏み砕かれちゃ駄目なんだ キミはキミのままでいい
You mustn't be crushed, you can stay just as you are.
声を上げて 私たちの歌は壊れない
Raise your voice, our song will never break.
その名を辿って 伝えるよ
Tracing that name, I'll convey it.
共鳴するの 私のストーリー
Resonating, my story
名前を呼んで そばにいるから
Call my name, because I'm by your side.
音を奏でよう 新しい世界
Let's play music in a new world.
キミに出会うために 生きていくんだ
I live on to meet you.
この場所が 奇跡だから
Because this place is a miracle.
リアルを超えて 繋ぐよ
Crossing reality, I'll connect it.
夜の深くに 眠りに落ちて
Falling asleep deep in the night,
やがて光が 世界を照らすよ
Soon the light will illuminate the world.
キミと出会えたこと 意味を見つけたのさ 共に分かち合って 生きていたい
Finding meaning in meeting you, I want to live sharing it together.
創造するの 私のストーリー
Creating my story
声を聞かせて キミを知りたいから
Let me hear your voice, because I want to know you.
開拓するの 新しい世界
Pioneering a new world
嘘じゃないんだ キミとのストーリー
It's not a lie, my story with you.
全てが始まる この場所で
In this place where everything begins,
歌を歌い続けるよ
I will keep on singing songs.
雑音が静寂に変わる瞬間を
The moment the jarring noise changes into silence,
絆が少しずつ欠ける惨劇を
the tragedies of each bond growing weaker little by little...
切り裂ければ楽になれた証拠を
Please don't overlook the proof
どうか見逃さないで
that it was easier to be torn apart.
置き去るのは過去だけでいい
Leave behind only the past.
feel across the borderline
now you're saved and you understand
さあ 神の指を舐めるの
Now, taste the finger of God.
貴方には低温な重さしか見えない
Only a cold weight is visible to you.
それなら秘密など共有出来ない
If that is so, secrets cannot be shared.
歯車が音を立てる時には
When the gears make a sound,
依存を自覚していて
be aware of your dependence
掴んだその手を放して
and let go of the hand you gripped.
feel across the borderline
now you're saved and you wake up
さあ この運命を辿るの
Now, pursue this fate.
奪うのが何を害しても
Whatever stealing harms,
世界は歪むのも惜しまずに
the world won't hesitate to warp.
feel across the borderline
シナリオも次々に変形を急ぐ
The scenario changes quickly in turn.
海底も明かりの漏れを思い出す
The seabed remembers the leak of light.
ざわめきと今手にした鍵で
With the turmoil and the key in hand,
自分が何を起こせる?
what can you bring about?
悲しみでも炎でも灯せる?
Can you light a flame with sadness?
feel across the borderline
now you're saved and you understand
さあ 神の指を舐めるの
Now, taste the finger of God.
あらゆる毒がその呼吸を
With every poison in your breath,
潜めては攻め合いを求めてる
you seek to lurk and attack each other.
feel across the borderline
声に出せないを それも
Even if you can't voice the pain of life,
生きている君のことを
you still acknowledge the life you're living.
木漏れ日とか温もりの
Let's acknowledge the past,
これまでを認めてあげよう
whether bathed in sunlight or warmth.
世界も不世界も偽物も本物も
World, fake world, fake things, real things...
見つけた想いがこの世界で
The feelings you found in this world,
みんなで
everyone...
ねえ ここだって君が来ても
Even if here is broken and even if you arrive,
不安の先は今は教えないよ
we won't teach you the future's uncertainty.
辿り着く君の手足で確かめるんだ
With your own hands and feet, you make sure
この時だって この場所だって
of the reason for your future existence,
未来の君の存在理由
even in this moment and in this place.
当たり前の価値を思う
Thinking of the ordinary value,
私たちの世界
our world...
今またこうして立ち出す君の背を
Now, once again, standing like this,
光の波が次の座標へと
light waves will guide you
導いていく
toward the next coordinates.
開いた大地に次の目が強く伸びる
Opening up to the first ground,
約束しようよ この先で
let's promise beyond this point.
ねえ ここだって君が笑って
Neh, even here, even if you laugh,
君が歌った奇跡の途中
even if you sing along the miraculous journey,
辿り着いた未来の意味を見つけに行くよ
finding the meaning of the future you reached,
この声だって この音だって
this voice and this sound,
次の世界に続いていくんだ
continuing into your next world,
当たり前の価値を掲げる僕らの世界
cherishing the ordinary value—
今の先へ
our world.